A Guide to the Floyd Gray Papers 1895-1908
Digital Library and Archive, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Digital Library and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Floyd Gray Papers 1895-1908
Digital Library and Archive, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Ms89-085
1 container; 0.5 cu. ft.
Papers of Floyd Gray, Bedford County Republican Committee chairman and distillery general storekeeper-gauger for the Internal Revenue Service. Includes correspondence and notes relating both to Gray's political activities and his civil service work. Also includes personal correspondence and financial records.
Dealer
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Floyd Gray Papers were purchased by the Digital Library and Archives in 1989.
Biographical/Historical Information
Floyd Gray, civil servant and Bedford County Republican Committee chairman, was born in Bedford County, Virginia on September 25, 1867. The son of Mercer H. and Ann Jane W. Robertson Gray, Floyd Gray played an active role in local politics and became chairman of the county's Republican Party committee in 1896. Around 1903, Gray was appointed a general storekeeper-gauger, charged with overseeing the operation and taxation of distilleries in Virginia's sixth internal revenue district. Because his civil service position forbade an active role in politics, Gray resigned from the chairmanship of the county's Republican organization in 1904. He was succeeded as chairman by his brother, W. B. Gray, but apparently continued to be the driving force behind the party's county organization. Floyd Gray died in Bedford County on December 5, 1941 and is buried in Gray Cemetery.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains the papers of Floyd Gray, a local Republican Party official and civil servant from Bedford County, Virginia. The collection contains correspondence and notes relating to Gray's work as chairman of the Bedford County Republican Party Committee, including many letters regarding party organization and appeals for assistance in obtaining local civil service positions. (A number of letters to W. B. Gray, who succeeded his brother as chair of the committee, are included as well.) The collection also contains correspondence, duty assignments and reports from Gray's general storekeeper-gauger civil service position. A small number of Gray's personal correspondence and financial records (including receipts, account statements, deeds, etc.) completes the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by subject matter, then chronologically.
Contents List
- Bedford County Republican Committee
  - 1902 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - 1903 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - 1904 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Jan-Jun 1905 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Jul-Dec 1905 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - 1906, n.d. (Box-folder 1-6)
- General storekeeper-gauger
  - Jan-Aug 1903 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Sep-Dec 1903 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Jan-Jun 1904 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Jul-Dec 1904 (Box-folder 1-10)
  - 1905-1908, n.d. (Box-folder 1-11)
- Personal correspondence and notes 1901-1905, n.d. (Box-folder 1-12)
- Personal financial records 1895-1908, n.d. (Box-folder 1-13)